# **Eric Vincent**

4237 Manuela Ave | Palo Alto, CA 94306 | evincent@gmail.com | eqvincent.github.io | 650 468 0664

### **Education Stanford University**

Class of 2020

Stanford, CA

Selected completed courses:

- CS 106X: Programming Abstractions Accelerated (advanced C++ foundational class)
- Breaking Codes & Finding Patterns (encryption; introductory information theory and number theory)
- CS 107: Computer Organization and Systems (C, data representation, machine-level code, computer arithmetic, and memory)
- CS 110: Principles of Computer Systems (filesystems, concurrency, networking)

## Henry M. Gunn High School

Class of 2016

Palo Alto, CA

Selected completed courses: AP Biology, AP AB Calculus, Programming Concepts (used Scheme), Introduction to Java, AP French, AP Micro/Macroeconomics

GPA: 3.79 unweighted, 3.96 weighted

*SAT:* 730 reading, 700 math, 760 writing (2190 total)

Institute for Mathematics and Computer Science 2013 - 2014 Online AP Computer Science: Java Programming (not allowed for sophomores at Gunn HS) *Grade:* A+, *AP Test Score:* 5 out of 5

#### Experience

<u>DeepMap</u>

Intern

Summer of 2017

Palo Alto, CA

DeepMap provides high definition 3D mapping as a service for self-driving cars.

- Robust ground and car detection in sparse LiDAR point clouds
- Object tracking and velocity estimation across multiple point clouds
- Used: C++

Savioke

Intern

Summer of 2016

San Jose, CA

Savioke builds the Relay, an autonomous, user-friendly room service robot for hotels.

- Enabled Relay robot to call external APIs
- Connected Relay to Amazon Alexa and the Amazon IOT Button
- Explored new interactive uses for Relay by using/extending visual robot scripting interface.
- Used: AWS, JavaScript with MeteorJS and ROS, Google Blockly

**Metanautix** (acquired by Microsoft) Intern Summer of 2015 Palo Alto, CA Enterprise software company focused on big data management, analytics, and visualization.

- Front-end web developer
- Used: AngularJS and Bootstrap

<u>Camio</u> Intern Summer of 2014 San Mateo, CA

Smart, cloud-based video monitoring and analytics for the home.

- Automatic graphing of company metrics
- Used: JavaScript and Google BigQuery with SQL

Foothills Summer Camp Counselor Summer of 2012 Foothills Park

Activities Competitive Gymnastics

2007 - 2016

Stanford Boys Gymnastics, San Mateo Gymnastics I was a competitive gymnast for nine years. I practiced ~20 hours per week year round. I was team captain from 2015 to 2016.

### Highlights:

Level 10 (2016) – JO Nationals: 5<sup>th</sup> place and all around finals. Regionals: 6<sup>th</sup> place and all-star team. States: 2<sup>nd</sup> place and all-star team.

Level 9 (2011-2013) – JO Nationals all three years, event finals on floor and pommel horse Level 6 (2009) – 4<sup>th</sup> place at State Championships, 1<sup>st</sup> place at Regional Championships.

#### **Gunn Robotics Team**

2014 - 2016

www.gunnrobotics.com

I was a member of my school's student-run FIRST robotics team for two years, and a member of the team's control systems group for one year. I have experience machining on a mill, lathe, drill press, band saw, and many other shop tools. In the controls group, I wrote python code to access several sensors and to control several mechanisms on the robot. I was an active member, and contributed upwards of 10 hours per week in addition to attending the competitions, helping our team win the FRC Team Spirit Award last year. In addition to coding and machining, I have written content for our team's website and business plan and have experience with CAD and basic electrical engineering.

#### **Ecole Nationale du Cirque**

2010 - 2012

ecolenationaledecirque.ca/en

I was accepted at the prestigious "National Circus School" in Montreal, Canada for three consecutive summers. While at the school I improved my skills in hand balancing, unicycling, and learned the German Wheel, Silks, and other disciplines of circus arts.

### **Graphic Arts, Stanford Open**

2011 - 2015

egvincent.com/stanford-open

For 5 consecutive years, I designed the T-shirt and logo for the "Stanford Open," an annual three-day gymnastics competition my gym hosts for over 800 gymnasts and their families.

#### **Programming Skills**

**Core**: proficient in C++, wrote clean and efficient C++ code in three separate Stanford courses as well as a summer software engineering internship.

Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS, MeteorJS, HTTP(S)

Scripting: Python, Bash, C#

Comfortable with Git (and in conjunction with GitHub or Gerrit)

Awards	AP Scholar with Distinction	2016	CollegeBoard
	Academic All American Recognition Award	2015: First Team honors 2014: Second Team honors	USA Gymnastics
	French National Contest	2013 (2C): Lauréat du Chapitre and Certificat d'Honneur	The American Association of Teachers of French
	Outstanding Accomplishments in the Visual Arts	2015	Gunn High School